<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vedant Writes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vedant Writes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>🚀 From GCS to BigQuery: Building Scalable ETL Pipelines with Apache Airflow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/from-gcs-to-bigquery-airflow-etl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/from-gcs-to-bigquery-airflow-etl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to move data from Google Cloud Storage to BigQuery, transform it, and make it analyst-friendly—all in a single, reliable pipeline? Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it with Airflow, and how you can too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-this-pipeline&#34;&gt;👋 Why This Pipeline?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest: data engineering isn&amp;rsquo;t just about crunching numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s about making sure the right data lands in the right place, in the right shape, every single time—even when the world throws you curveballs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero to Blog: A Lazy Engineer&#39;s Guide to Automating Web Presence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/blog-automation-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/blog-automation-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a &lt;strong&gt;lazy 10x engineer&lt;/strong&gt; like me, you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate the art of doing less while achieving more. Setting up a blog? Sounds like manual work—&lt;em&gt;ew&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, I automated the entire process with a CI/CD pipeline using &lt;strong&gt;Hugo&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Netlify&lt;/strong&gt;, and a custom subdomain via &lt;strong&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I transformed my blog into a professional, self-updating masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-outcome&#34;&gt;The Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated deployment:&lt;/strong&gt; Push to GitHub, and Netlify does the rest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customized blog theme:&lt;/strong&gt; No cookie-cutter themes here.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom subdomain:&lt;/strong&gt; Because &lt;code&gt;blog.vedant.cloud&lt;/code&gt; screams professionalism.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero manual effort:&lt;/strong&gt; The ultimate lazy 10x engineer flex.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-install-hugo-fast-because-who-has-time&#34;&gt;Step 1: Install Hugo (Fast, because who has time?)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First things first, I needed Hugo—a static site generator. On macOS, I installed it with a single command using &lt;strong&gt;Homebrew&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Donec sed odio dui.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Donec sed odio dui. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Praesent commodo cursus magna, vel scelerisque nisl consectetur et.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros. Integer posuere erat a ante venenatis dapibus posuere velit aliquet. Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
